There are three things that can affect your project in your organization.
That's your policies the processes and the procedures.
So these are unique to each organization.
So policies processes and procedures.
Let's take a look at how these affect the different areas from initiation the way the closing of our
project.
First off internal processes for project management this is unique to your organization.
So how do you manage the project.
How is your project structured.
What's the framework of your project.
The whole place the framework of best practices.
So it's the generally accepted practices or best practices of project management.
How does your organization manage projects sort of using a predictive lifecycle or an adaptive lifecycle.
Do they have a PMO that you have to work with the structure of the company affects the amount of authority
that you have as well.
So these can be enterprise environmental factors or organizational process assets.
So internal processes for project management are unique to your company within initiation.
In planning there are some policies and processes procedures that affect how you do these activities.
So what about the criteria for tailoring your standard processes and procedures.
So are you allowed to tailor the processes.
And if you are to what depth and who makes that determination or makes that approval organizational
standards are things that are unique to your organization but also to your industry.
So think about your H.R. policies but also think about like health and safety policies.
So if you're in healthcare or construction or manufacturing you have some health and safety policies.
Also security and confidentiality policies how we use secure data how who has access to that data.
What about confidentiality when you deal with team members is sometimes this project managers were privy
to data that not everyone should see like financial data quality policies procurement policies environmental
policies.
These are all things that we have to consider as we do planning or we start the project the product
and project life cycles.
So you think about what you're creating.
How does that affect how you'll do the work.
So in construction there are some predefined phases generally that follow construction or NIIT or in
software development or in health care the project lifecycle remember is the phases of the project.
It's not initiating planning executing controlling closing we're talking about the phases.
So the foundation the framing the electrical and so on.
So one of the phases that you have how you audit your process is to determine if they're accurate and
you're doing them well and how can you improve upon them.
What will be your improvement targets he set some goals for your improvement like fewer number of defects
or fewer number of tasks that are late and in standard process definitions.
So these are all things that we do in initiating and planning a couple of more we need to look at here
in initiating and planning.
I've already mentioned templates so templates can be used for project management documents.
Are plans different forms so member templates can be from historical information.
Or they can be created for us that are standard to our organization.
So in initiating and planning we need to know what templates or forms must we use or is expected of
us to use.
So you think about those different areas of your project and different registers.
We have a risk register a stakeholder register an issue log.
So there are some templates already created for you contract templates different reporting templates
like a Risk Report where your status report or variants report.
So those are all things that can be created for you or adapted.
And then if you are doing procurement You may have a preapproved vendor list or a supplier list and
that's internal to your organization.
It's a list this is you can purchase from these vendors.
They've already been approved.
You can choose whichever one is most appropriate for you.
So those are some things that affect how we do initiating and planning.
Let's talk about some processes and policies and procedures that affect our execution monitoring and
controlling the big one is change control change control is a huge process in your exam.
Change Control is how we look at changes from scope schedule cost in procurement.
Now all walk through in Chapter 4 The Pinback the integrated change is something that we do the change
control procedures are unique though to your organization that we still want to do integrated change
control but how you do it is unique to your organization.
So there may be a form that someone has to fill out and hand you or email to you or he may have a database
set up where people can go to a website that's internals your company and fill out a form and that enters
the change control workflow.
So how do people submit changes.
Do you have a change control board that reviews changes or can the project manager approve changes or
you may have a threshold where anything below 10000 we consider anything that's going to cost more than
10000.
It's declined.
So one of the procedures there we need some traceability matrix sees a traceability matrix as a table
typically used in requirements.
But we have all of our requirements listed and that it tracks it through each phase of the project until
it's done.
We'll talk more about that in chapter 5 in the Pinback when we get into scope management.
But it's called the requirements traceability matrix.
We can also use it for risk issues and a few other places.
What are your financial control procedures.
So do you have a project budget that you have to track the time against your accounting for your project
team members time and there's a financial aspect of that.
What about the resources that you use and you track the finances against that.
So how will you track the financial procedures.
Also the pin if you're doing an internal project versus that extra project where there's a profit margin
to consider sort of financial control procedures these are a process that's in a policy that's going
to be unique to the organization and just a standard for the Pinback.
This is something that touches your project that's created by your organization.
What about issue and defect management.
So your issue log and your defect in that how do you do the factory pair or corrective actions.
So how do you manage that internally and then resource availability.
So you have resource calendars at it how do you schedule those or reserve equipment or facilities and
that assignment management how determine which determine which resource does what activity and then
who want to distribute that work across the resources.
So one person not the only one who's doing the fun activities or the not so fun activities but how do
you distribute it.
It's not about fun or not fun.
You're saying you don't want to make sure that everyone has an opportunity to contribute but also that
you're using all of your resources affectively also executing monitoring controlling you have communication
requirements.
We have procedures for prioritizing and improving our work authorization just what I was talking about
the distribution of work but also how then do people go about doing the work how do they know they have
an assignment.
What's that look like in your organization.
Any templates that have to be updated or that you have to follow up.
So the risk register as risk identified you update that risk register.
Same with the issue log and the change log.
What are some standardized guidelines work extra instructions proposals performance measurement how
do you know you're doing well.
How do you know a vendor is doing well.
So how do you audit and track their performance.
And then we need some way of doing some validation of our product that a service or a result.
So how do you validate that.
How do you prove that what you did was what you planned.
All right so these are processes policies and procedures that affect how we manage our projects.
Keep moving forward.